British Columbia women's history audio collection
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
British Columbia women's history audio collection
1989
F-148
Q106660071
7 cm of textual records 12 sound recordings
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION Sound recordings (original and copies) include 34 audio cassettes and 8 optical discs and 65 .wav files.
Financial assistance for the arrangement and description of these records and production of the finding aid was generously provided by the Government of Canada through the National Archival Development Program, a program delivered by the Canadian Council of Archives in partnership with Library and Archives Canada (March 2009).
McPherson, Kathryn
In the spring semester 1989, Kathryn McPherson was instructor for Women Studies 202, "History of Women in Canada." As part of the course work, McPherson assigned students to conduct a 2-3 hour interview with a British Columbia woman. Students were encouraged to select a woman over 60 years of age, and the interviewer was responsible for the themes covered. The interviews were recorded and deposited in the Archives.
published
Full
Revised
Title was provided by the course instructor, Kathryn McPherson, and is based on the contents of the collection.
The collection consists of audio cassette recordings of the interviews and associated paper documentation (biographical forms and interview summaries) for each of the women who participated. Twelve women were interviewed. The names of the interviewers and interviewees are:
* Beverly Ann Carlson interviewed by Anda Jones.
* Bertha Cochrane interviewed by Linda Henderson.
* Suzanne Crawford interviewed by Pat Newton.
* Kathleen Dawson interviewed by Linda Cluelett.
* Ann St. Clair Ecclestone inteviewed by Jane Ecclestone.
* Jean Ferguson interviewed by Marsha Ferguson.
* Melitha Rose Kraus interviewed by Laurie Doig.
* Patricia Mazzarella Larson interviewed by Angela M. Larson.
* Violet Piersma interviewed by Peter van Drongelen.
* Florence Vilma Shannon; interviewer not recorded.
* Miyako Shinkawa interviewed by Debbie Shinkawa.
* Ilo Urquart; interviewer not recorded.
Note that there is no paper documentation for one of the interviewees (Ilo Urquart).
Arrangement of the collection was provided by the archivist, with separate series for the cassettes and paper documentation.
McPherson, Kathryn; Sound recordings; Textual records; Women; Community life; Family and personal life
The material was donated to the Archives by the course instructor, Kathryn McPherson, in 1989. The project generated 38 audio cassettes, but four of them were not included in the original transfer in 1989 on the request of the interviewee.
As of April 2009, all accessions have been processed. No further accruals are expected.
For other oral histories relating to women in BC, see the Frances Wasserlein fonds (F-162).
Access to the original sound recordings is restricted for preservation reasons due to the fragility of the storage medium (audio cassettes). Audio cassettes have been digitized for access copies.
Copyright subsists in all or some of the records. The interviewers did not transfer copyright to the SFU Archives at the time of transfer, nor did they explicitly grant the Archives permission to release their personal contact information to those researchers wishing to discuss the use of copyrighted material. Permission to use copyright material is therefore managed on a case-by-case basis. Please consult the reference archivist for more details.
File and item lists are avaiable. Appendix A contains a copy of Kathryn McPherson's overview of the materials and the context in which they were generated.
- Oral history interviews: biographical forms and summaries, 1989; F-148-1; 7 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of the paper documentation associated with each interview subject. Records consist of biographical forms and oral history interview summaries. The biographical form captures the participant's personal data inlcuding information relating to the subject's occupation, places lived, education and employment history, parents, spouses, children. The oral history interview summary forms were prepared by the interviewers to summarize the contents of each cassette tape.
  Arrangement was provided by the archivist; separate files were created for each interviewee; files are arranged alphabetically.
  - Carlson, Bev, 1989; F-148-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - small 148-1)
    Carlson, Beverly Ann; Jones, Anda; Textual records
    Open
  - Cochrane, Bertha, 1989; F-148-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - small 148-1)
    Cochrane, Bertha; Henderson, Linda; Textual records
  - Crawford, Suzanne, 1989; F-148-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - small 148-1)
    Crawford, Suzanne; Newton, Pat; Textual records
  - Dawson, Kathleen, 1989; F-148-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - small 148-1)
    Dawson, Kathleen; Cluelett, Linda; Textual records
  - Ecclestone, Ann St. Clair, 1989; F-148-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - small 148-1)
    Ecclestone, Ann St. Clair; Ecclestone, Jane; Textual records
  - Ferguson, Jean, 1989; F-148-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - small 148-1)
    Ferguson, Jean; Ferguson, Marsha; Textual records
  - Kraus, Melitha Rose, 1989; F-148-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - small 148-1)
    Kraus, Melitha Rose; Doig, Laurie; Textual records
  - Larson, Patricia M., 1989; F-148-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - small 148-1)
    Larson, Patricia Mazzarella; Larson, Angela M.; Textual records
  - Piersma, Violet, 1989; F-148-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - small 148-1)
    Piersma, Violet; van Drongelen, Peter; Textual records
  - Shannon, Florence Vilma, 1989; F-148-1-0-0-10 (Archival box - small 148-1)
    Shannon, Florence Vilma; Textual records
  - Shinkawa, Miyaka, 1989; F-148-1-0-0-11 (Archival box - small 148-1)
    Shinkawa, Debbie; Shinkawa, Miyako; Textual records
- Oral history interviews: audio cassettes, 1989; F-148-2; 12 sound recordings; Physical description: includes 34 audio cassettes and 8 optical discs.
  Series consists of the audio recordings of the interviews. Note that there were originally three cassettes for Ann Ecclestone, but on the request of the interviewee only two of these were included in the transfer of material to the Archives.
  Arrangement was provided by the archivist; cassettes are arranged alphabetically by interviewee.
  Access to the original sound recordings is restricted for preservation reasons due to the fragility of the storage medium (audio cassette). Digital access copies exist for the audio cassettes.
  - Carlson, Bev, 1989; F-148-2-0-0-0-1; 3 audio cassettes 6 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-3313, Audio cassette OBJ-3314, Audio cassette OBJ-3315)
    Carlson, Beverly Ann; Jones, Anda; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-3313_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3313_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3314_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3314_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3315_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3315_SideB.wav
  - Cochrane, Bertha, 1989; F-148-2-0-0-0-2; 3 audio cassettes 6 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-3316, Audio cassette OBJ-3317, Audio cassette OBJ-3318, Optical disc: cd OBJ-3347, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3348, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3349)
    Cochrane, Bertha; Henderson, Linda; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-3316_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3316_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3317_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3317_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3318_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3318_SideB.wav
  - Crawford, Suzanne, 1989; F-148-2-0-0-0-3; 3 audio cassettes 6 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-3319, Audio cassette OBJ-3320, Audio cassette OBJ-3321)
    Crawford, Suzanne; Newton, Pat; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-3319_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3319_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3320_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3320_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3321_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3321_SideB.wav
  - Dawson, Kathleen, 1989; F-148-2-0-0-0-4; 3 audio cassettes 5 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-3322, Audio cassette OBJ-3323, Audio cassette OBJ-3324)
    Dawson, Kathleen; Cluelett, Linda; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-3322_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3323_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3323_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3324_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3324_SideB.wav
  - Ecclestone, Ann St. Clair, 1989; F-148-2-0-0-0-5; 2 audio cassettes 2 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-3325, Audio cassette OBJ-3326)
    Ecclestone, Ann St. Clair; Ecclestone, Jane; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    OBJ-3326 is blank.
    - OBJ-3325_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3325_SideB.wav
  - Ferguson, Jean, 1989; F-148-2-0-0-0-6; 3 audio cassettes 6 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-3327, Audio cassette OBJ-3328, Audio cassette OBJ-3329)
    Ferguson, Jean; Ferguson, Marsha; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-3327_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3327_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3328_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3328_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3329_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3329_SideB.wav
  - Kraus, Melitha Rose, 1989; F-148-2-0-0-0-7; 3 audio cassettes 3 optical disks 6 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-3330, Audio cassette OBJ-3331, Audio cassette OBJ-3332, Optical disc: cd OBJ-3350, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3351, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3352)
    Kraus, Melitha Rose; Doig, Laurie; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-3330_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3330_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3331_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3331_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3332_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3332_SideB.wav
  - Larson, Patricia M., 1989; F-148-2-0-0-0-8; 3 audio cassettes 6 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-3333, Audio cassette OBJ-3334, Audio cassette OBJ-3335)
    Larson, Angela M.; Larson, Patricia Mazzarella; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-3333_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3333_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3334_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3334_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3335_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3335_SideB.wav
  - Piersma, Violet, 1989; F-148-2-0-0-0-9; 2 audio cassettes 2 optical disks 4 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-3336, Audio cassette OBJ-3337, Optical disc: cd OBJ-3353, Optical disc: dvd OBJ-3354)
    Piersma, Violet; van Drongelen, Peter; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-3336_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3336_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3337_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3337_SideB.wav
  - Shannon, Florence V., 1989; F-148-2-0-0-0-10; 3 audio cassettes 6 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-3338, Audio cassette OBJ-3339, Audio cassette OBJ-3340)
    Shannon, Florence Vilma; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-3338_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3338_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3339_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3339_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3340_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3340_SideB.wav
  - Shinkawa, Miyako, 1989; F-148-2-0-0-0-11; 3 audio cassettes 6 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-3341, Audio cassette OBJ-3342, Audio cassette OBJ-3343)
    Shinkawa, Debbie; Shinkawa, Miyako; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-3341_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3341_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3342_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3342_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3343_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3343_SideB.wav
  - Urquart, Ilo, 1989; F-148-2-0-0-0-12; 3 audio cassettes 6 .wav files (Audio cassette OBJ-3344, Audio cassette OBJ-3345, Audio cassette OBJ-3346)
    Urquart, Ilo; Sound recordings; Records in electronic form (digitized)
    - OBJ-3344_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3344_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3345_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3345_SideB.wav
    - OBJ-3346_SideA.wav
    - OBJ-3346_SideB.wav